Guide to the Mercedes Moore DeMare Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Mercedes Moore DeMare Papers
1930-1936
MS 1702
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
The papers consist of student notebooks, syllabi, and other course materials belonging to Mercedes Moore DeMare, a 1936 M.F.A. graduate of the drama program in the Yale University School of the Fine Arts.
DeMare, Mercedes Moore
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Woodstock, NY, Library, 1995. Gift of Mercedes Moore DeMare, 1996.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Mercedes Moore DeMare was born on November 7, 1910 in Brooklyn, New York. She graduated from Smith College in 1931 and received a M.F.A. from the Yale University School of the Fine Arts in 1936. Her costume and scenic designs appeared in various Broadway productions during the 1930s and 1940s.
Arrangement
Arranged by type of material.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of student notebooks, syllabi, and other course materials belonging to Mercedes Moore DeMare, a 1936 M.F.A. graduate of the drama program in the Yale University School of the Fine Arts.
Drama -- Study and teaching; DeMare, Mercedes Moore; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Department of Drama
- Series I
  - Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Course materials
    - Art 26 [Smith College?] 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Drama 9, The Theatre - its Productions, Organizations, and Maintenance
      - General, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Bound syllabus, "Elementary Play Production," Alexander Dean and Philip W. Barber, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Drama 12, Scenic Design, its Background and Practice, [1932-1933?] (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Drama 14, Stage Lighting, Elementary Practice, [1932-1933?] (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Drama 15, Costume Design, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Drama 18, Play Directing [includes: bound syllabus, "Play Directing," Alexander Dean, 1931], 1933. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Drama 122, Decorative Arts in Relation to Scenic Design, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Drama 142, Advanced Stage Design: Scenery and Costumes, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Stage lighting - "Laboratory notes," Stanley McCandless, 1930. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Italian painting - notes (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Stage design - notes (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
    - Programs (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Additional Material, 1936; Accession 1996-M-111
  - Scenic and costume designs for a production of The Dog Beneath the Skin [Master of Fine Arts thesis presented to the Yale University School of Fine Arts], 1936 (Box 1)